Guide to the Goodwin J. (Goodwin Jess) Knight Papers, 1896-1988 (inclusive), 1946-1970 (bulk)
Department of Special Collections
Goodwin J. (Goodwin Jess) Knight Papers,
1896-1988 (inclusive), 1946-1970 (bulk)
M0244
Knight, Goodwin J. (Goodwin Jess), 1896-1970.
213 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Goodwin Jess Knight, born 9 December 1896 in Provo, Utah, received his A.B. degree in law from Stanford in 1919 and was admitted to the California Bar in March 1921. In 1935 he was appointed to the Los Angeles Superior Court, in 1946 he became Lieutenant Governor of California, and in 1954 he was elected Governor. Knight died 22 May 1970.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Clippings restricted: require 24 hr. paging period.
The Media materials require at least two weeks advance notice to use in order to allow staff time to have use copies made from the original items.
Provenance
Gift of Virginia Carlson Knight, 1973, 1974, 1982, 1987, and 1988.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Virginia Carlson Knight, 1973, 1974, 1982, 1987, and 1988.
Provenance
Gift of Virginia Carlson Knight, 1973, 1974, 1982, 1987, and 1988.
Biographical Note
Goodwin Jess Knight, born 9 December 1896 in Provo, Utah, received his A.B. degree in law from Stanford in 1919 and was admitted to the California Bar in March 1921. In 1935 he was appointed to the Los Angeles Superior Court, in 1946 he became Lieutenant Governor of California, and in 1954 he was elected Governor. Knight died 22 May 1970.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Ahmanson, Howard, 1906-1968.; Alioto, Joseph.; Anderson, Glenn M.; Arthur, Chester Alan, 1829-1886.; Barrett, Douglas.; Behrens, Earl C.; Belli, Melvin M., 1907-; Brand, Harry.; Brennan, Bernard C.; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-; Burkett, William A.; Christopher, George.; Dargan, Vernon C.; Edgerton, J. Howard.; Flournoy, Houston I.; Hahn, Gordon R.; Hauk, A. Andrew.; Helms, Paul.; Jones, Herbert C. (Herbert Coffin), b.1881?.; Kaufman, Herbert C.; Kelly, Earl Lee.; Knight, Goodwin, 1896-1970.; Land, Pearl.; Lurie, Louis R.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964.; Mason, Paul, 1898-; McComb, Marshall.; Milias, George W.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Phillips, Patrick Henry.; Polland, Milton R.; Rafferty, Max Lewis, 1917-; Storke, Thomas M.; Thompson, John F.; Warren, Earl, 1891-1974.; Republican Party (Calif.); Stanford University.; California--Politics and government--1850-1950.; California--Politics and government--1951-; Motion pictures.
Scope and Content
The Knight Papers consist of political and personal correspondence, speeches, office claendars, press releases, pamphlets and magazines, information cards, clippings, scrapbooks, condolences, audio-visual materials, photographs, books, memorabilia, legal papers and the manuscript and printed form of a book written by Goodwin Knight as a child, Good's Budget of Stories for Boys (1910). The body of the collection concerns the years 1946-1958 although materials included range from 1910 to 1970.
The political scope of the materials is very broad, touching on such prominent political figures as George Christopher, Earl Warren, Edmund Brown, Richard Nixon, William Knowland and Dwight D. Eisenhower, to mention a few.
The major campaigns covered are: the 1946 and 1950 races for Lieutenant Governor; the gubernatorial race of 1954, and the unsuccessful campaign for U. S. Senate in 1958. Knight ran against Richard Nixon in the Republican primary of 1962 but was forced to retire from the race because of ill health. All campaigns are covered primarily on a statewide basis, although national elections may be highlighted through the printed reference materials.
The personal correspondence mentions many civic, personal and business-oriented organizations to which Knight belonged or by whom he was cited. Some material concerns his early life and education and family matters.
The collection should be of interest to the contemporary historian as it reflects the wake of New Deal politics in California, the impact of unamericanism within the state and the nation, and the rise of a new ecological awareness. Many of the issues raised during the Knight years became the foundations of contemporary problems facing not only California, but the United States as a whole. The correspondence gives substantial insight into the social attitudes of the 1950's.
Materials from the second accession of the Goodwin Knight Papers (M0245) have been incorporated into this larger collection (M0244) of Knight materials. These additions have been noted in the series and subseries descriptions where they occur.
Some of the materials in this section overlap Part I (M0244); the majority, however, pertains to the period from 1958 to 1970. Personal and political correspondence have not been separated. "Personality" files dealing with certain important political figures have been intreduced, which include correspondence and related materials.
The tone of this second segment of the Knight Papers is primarily political and often reflects Knight's political clashes within ghe Republican Party. Much of the material here will provide invaluable information to the contemporary politcal scientist and historian.
Organization
Data organization: Nine series: 1. Correspondence, 1896-1970. 2. Printed Reference Materials, 1946-1958. 3. Clippings, 1948-1970. 4. Condolences, 1952. 5. Scrapbooks, 1944-1958. 6. Books. 7. Audio-visual Materials. 8. Photographs. 9. Memorabilia.
Container List
Disclaimer: the original guide to this collection was created in an era before electronic word processing. Staff emended the guide by hand on numerous occasions. These additions, corrections, and notations have been captured in a good-faith effort by the staff encoding this guide. However, it is likely that researchers will need to work with staff from the Manuscripts Division to verify the location of materials of interest.
- Series 1. Correspondence
  The correspondence is divided into personal and political categories. The political correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent within each chronological unit. Subject folders were left in their original order and were placed at the end of the straight alphabetical sequence. In the personal category, folders were left in their original order except where obvious filing errors were found. In all cases, headings should be checked under officers and mdmbers of corporate bodies as well as under the corporate title.
  - Subseries 1. Political Correspondence
    - 1944-46Political Correspondence (a-z). (Box 1-3, Folder 1-19)
      - Republican Party Platform 1944, Accession no. M0244 (Folder 1)
      - Republican National Convention1944, Accession no. M0244 (Folder 1)
      - Clippings-Misc., Accession no. M0244 (Folder 1)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - B-Berg, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Berk-Byrd, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - C-Clough, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Cober-Curtis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - D, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - E-F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - H-I, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - J-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Mc, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - N-O, Accession no. M0244 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - P-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - S, Accession no. M0244 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - T-V, Accession no. M0244 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - W-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - [unittitle added: see error report]
      - Speakers list to campaign., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Newspaper publishers master list., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - Republican Party platform., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      - Campaign contributors list., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 38)
      - S.F. Co. Republican Central Committee correspondence., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 39)
      - News releases., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 40)
      - Party lists - many prominent Republicans., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - Miscellaneous markers for election business., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 2032)
      - Congratulatory telegrams., Accession no. M0244 (Box 4, Folder 3334)
      - Checkbooks for Citizens Com. for GJK (2), Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 42)
      - Republican organization budgets., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 43)
      - Press releases., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - Rep. State Central Com. on Perm. Org. Minutes., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Invoices and expenditures., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - Advertising (primarily Lockwood-Shackelford)., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - Unclassified., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Pamphlets., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Vote analysis by Assembly/Congressional district., Accession no. M0244 (Box 5, Folder 445)
    - [unittitle added: see error report]
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 6, Folder 52)
      - B, Accession no. M0244 (Box 6, Folder 53)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 6, Folder 54)
      - D-F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 6, Folder 55)
      - G-H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 7, Folder 56)
      - I-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 7, Folder 57)
      - L-M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 7, Folder 58)
      - Mc-O, Accession no. M0244 (Box 7, Folder 59)
      - P-R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - S, Accession no. M0244 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - T-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Junior Statesman of America., Accession no. M0244 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - 1948Political Correspondence (a-z plus subj.) (Box 9-13, Folder 64-93)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - B, Accession no. M0244 (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 9, Folder 67)
      - D, Accession no. M0244 (Box 10, Folder 68)
      - E-F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 10, Folder 69)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 10, Folder 70)
      - H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 10, Folder 71)
      - I-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 11, Folder 72)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 11, Folder 73)
      - M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 11, Folder 74)
      - Mc-O, Accession no. M0244 (Box 11, Folder 75)
      - P-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 12, Folder 76)
      - R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 12, Folder 77)
      - S-Sk, Accession no. M0244 (Box 12, Folder 78)
      - Sl-T, Accession no. M0244 (Box 12, Folder 79)
      - U-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 80)
      - Eggars, Arthur, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 81)
      - Houser Crime Commission, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 82)
      - Houser Crime Commission Press Releases, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 83)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 84)
      - National Probation and Patrol Assn., Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 85)
      - Press Releases, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 86)
      - Protocol, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 87)
      - Republican Central Committees, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 88)
      - Republican Natl. Convention 1948, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 89)
      - Republican Party, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 90)
      - Republican Spokesman, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 91)
      - Republican State Convention, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 92)
      - San Gabriel Valley Republican Women's Club, Accession no. M0244 (Box 13, Folder 93)
    - 1949 Political Correspondence (a-z plus subj.) (Box 14-19, Folder 94-126)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 14, Folder 94)
      - B, Accession no. M0244 (Box 14, Folder 95)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 14, Folder 96)
      - D, Accession no. M0244 (Box 14, Folder 97)
      - E-F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 15, Folder 98)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 15, Folder 99)
      - H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 15, Folder 100)
      - I-J, Accession no. M0244 (Box 15, Folder 101)
      - K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 16, Folder 102)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 16, Folder 103)
      - M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 16, Folder 104)
      - Mc-O, Accession no. M0244 (Box 16, Folder 105)
      - P-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 17, Folder 106)
      - R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 17, Folder 107)
      - S-Sn, Accession no. M0244 (Box 17, Folder 108)
      - Si-Sz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 17, Folder 109)
      - T, Accession no. M0244 (Box 18, Folder 110)
      - U-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 18, Folder 111)
      - Invitations, Accession no. M0244 (Box 18, Folder 112)
      - Invitations, Accession no. M0244 (Box 18, Folder 113)
      - Invitations, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 114)
      - Cal. Med. Assn., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 115)
      - Cancer Prevention Society, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 116)
      - Demo. Co. Central Com., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 117)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 118)
      - Natl. Probation & Parole Assn., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 119)
      - Rep. Assly. of S.F., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 120)
      - Rep. Cent. Com. - L.A., San Bernardino, S.F., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 121)
      - Rep. Pty., Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 122)
      - Cal. Ccl. Rep. Women, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 123)
      - Rep. Women San Diego, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 124)
      - State Societies, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 125)
      - Synon, John, Accession no. M0244 (Box 19, Folder 126)
    - 1950Correspondence (Box 20-23, Folder 127-141)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 20, Folder 127)
      - B, Accession no. M0244 (Box 20, Folder 128)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 20, Folder 129)
      - D-F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 20, Folder 130)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 21, Folder 131)
      - H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 21, Folder 132)
      - I-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 21, Folder 133)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 21, Folder 134)
      - M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 22, Folder 135)
      - N-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 22, Folder 136)
      - R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 22, Folder 137)
      - S, Accession no. M0244 (Box 22, Folder 138)
      - T-V, Accession no. M0244 (Box 23, Folder 139)
      - W-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 23, Folder 140)
      - Miscellany re: election, Accession no. M0244 (Box 23, Folder 141)
    - Campaign Correspondence 1950 (Box 24-25, Folder 142-148)
      - A-C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 24, Folder 142)
      - D-G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 24, Folder 143)
      - H-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 24, Folder 144)
      - L-M, Accession no. M0244 (Box 24, Folder 145)
      - N-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 25, Folder 146)
      - R-S, Accession no. M0244 (Box 25, Folder 147)
      - T-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 25, Folder 148)
    - Name Index (Box 26-27, Folder 149-171)
      - Acheson, Dean, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 149)
      - Baker, Glenn, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 150)
      - Brown, Pat, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 151)
      - Downey, Sheridan, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 152)
      - Eisenhower, D.D., Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 153)
      - Eisenhower, clippings, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 154)
      - Finch, Robt. H., Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 155)
      - Kimball, Dan, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 156)
      - Lake, Alexander, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 157)
      - MacArthur, Douglas, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 158)
      - Miller, George, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 159)
      - Nixon, Richard M., Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 160)
      - Pacht, Isaac, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 161)
      - Palmer, Kyle, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 162)
      - Patterson, Ellis E., Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 163)
      - Parrish, Lew, Accession no. M0244 (Box 26, Folder 164)
      - Penaat, Bill, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 164)
      - Robinson, E.E., Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 165)
      - Roosevelt, James, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 166)
      - Samish, Artie, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 167)
      - Shattuck, Ed, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 168)
      - Simpson, Roy, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 169)
      - Taft, Robert A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 170)
      - Warren, Earl, Accession no. M0244 (Box 27, Folder 171)
    - 1950 -Miscellany (Box 28-29, Folder 172-200)
      - Ad mats for campaign, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 172)
      - Agricultural Reports, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 173)
      - Calif. Farm Bureau Fed., Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 174)
      - Calif. Hay, Grain & Feed Dealers Assoc., Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 175)
      - Cancer Prevention Society, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 176)
      - Central Calif. Berry Growers Assoc., Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 177)
      - Congratulations, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 178)
      - Crusade for Freedom, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 179)
      - Deposit Slips, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 180)
      - Editorials, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 181)
      - Farming Articles, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 182)
      - Health Insurance, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 183)
      - Invoices, Accession no. M0244 (Box 28, Folder 184)
      - Lumber Merchants Assoc., Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 185)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 186)
      - Natl. Probation & Parole Assoc., Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 187)
      - Releases I, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 188)
      - Releases II, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 189)
      - Republican Cent. Comm. Contra Costa County, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 190)
      - Republican Cent. Comm. L.A. County, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 191)
      - Republican Cent. Comm. San Mateo County, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 192)
      - Repub. Party, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 193)
      - Repub. State Cent. Comm., Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 194)
      - Repub. State Convention, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 195)
      - Santa Cruz, Chamber of Commerce, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 196)
      - Western Mining Council, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 197)
      - Misc., Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 198)
      - Carter, Oliver _____Empty, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 199)
      - Luckey, George _____Empty, Accession no. M0244 (Box 29, Folder 200)
    - 1951Political Correspondence (a-z) (Box 30-34, Folder 201-237)
      - A (Box 30, Folder 201)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 30, Folder 201)
      - B, Accession no. M0244 (Box 30, Folder 202)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 30, Folder 203)
      - Calif, Accession no. M0244 (Box 30, Folder 204)
      - D, Accession no. M0244 (Box 31, Folder 205)
      - E, Accession no. M0244 (Box 31, Folder 206)
      - F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 31, Folder 207)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 31, Folder 208)
      - H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 31, Folder 209)
      - I-J, Accession no. M0244 (Box 32, Folder 210)
      - K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 32, Folder 211)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 32, Folder 212)
      - M-Mc, Accession no. M0244 (Box 32, Folder 213)
      - Me-Mz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 32, Folder 214)
      - N-O, Accession no. M0244 (Box 33, Folder 215)
      - P, Accession no. M0244 (Box 33, Folder 216)
      - Q-R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 33, Folder 217)
      - S-Sl, Accession no. M0244 (Box 33, Folder 218)
      - Sm-Sz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 33, Folder 219)
      - T, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 220)
      - U-V, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 221)
      - W, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 222)
      - X-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 223)
      - Cancer Prevention, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 224)
      - Community Chest, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 225)
      - League of California Cities, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 226)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 227)
      - Republican Club - Westwood Young, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 228)
      - Rep. Central Com. - Los Angeles Co., Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 229)
      - Rep. Central Com. - San Francisco Co., Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 230)
      - Republican Party, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 231)
      - Republican State Central Committee, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 232)
      - Republican Co. Central Com. Chairmen, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 233)
      - California Council of Republican Women, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 234)
      - Republican Women of Southern California, Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 235)
      - United Cerebral Palsy Association., Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 236)
      - Western Mining Council 1951., Accession no. M0244 (Box 34, Folder 237)
    - 1952Political Correspondence (a-z) (Box 35-40, Folder 238-270)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 238)
      - Ba-Bl, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 239)
      - Bo-Bz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 240)
      - Ca-Ch, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 241)
      - Cl-Cz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 242)
      - Calif, Accession no. M0244 (Box 35, Folder 243)
      - D, Accession no. M0244 (Box 36, Folder 244)
      - E, Accession no. M0244 (Box 36, Folder 245)
      - F, Accession no. M0244 (Box 36, Folder 246)
      - G, Accession no. M0244 (Box 36, Folder 247)
      - H, Accession no. M0244 (Box 37, Folder 248)
      - I-K, Accession no. M0244 (Box 37, Folder 249)
      - L, Accession no. M0244 (Box 37, Folder 250)
      - Ma-McKay, Accession no. M0244 (Box 38, Folder 251)
      - McKay-Mz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 38, Folder 252)
      - N-Q, Accession no. M0244 (Box 38, Folder 253)
      - R, Accession no. M0244 (Box 39, Folder 254)
      - Calif, Accession no. M0244 (Box 39, Folder 255)
      - Sa-Sm, Accession no. M0244 (Box 39, Folder 256)
      - Sn-Sz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 39, Folder 257)
      - T, Accession no. M0244 (Box 39, Folder 258)
      - U-V, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 259)
      - W, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 260)
      - X-Z, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 261)
      - Cancer Prevention Society, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 262)
      - Community Chest, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 263)
      - Multiple Sclerosis, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 264)
      - National Rep. Convention Information, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 265)
      - Presidential Election, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 266)
      - Rep. Central Com. L.A. County, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 267)
      - Republican State Central Committee, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 268)
      - Republican Party, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 269)
      - Veterans of Foreign Wars, Accession no. M0244 (Box 40, Folder 270)
    - 1953Political Correspondence (a-z) (Box 41-45, Folder 271-296)
      - A, Accession no. M0244 (Box 41, Folder 271)
      - Ba-Bot, Accession no. M0244 (Box 41, Folder 272)
      - Bou-Bz, Accession no. M0244 (Box 41, Folder 273)
      - C, Accession no. M0244 (Box 41, Folder 274)